<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="1" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />The revelation which Habakkuk the prophet saw. <verse number="2" style="v" />Yahweh,<note style="f" caller="+"></note> how long will I cry, and you will not hear? I cry out to you “Violence!” and will you not save? <verse number="3" style="v" />Why do you show me iniquity, and look at perversity? For destruction and violence are before me. There is strife, and contention rises up. <verse number="4" style="v" />Therefore the law is paralyzed, and justice never prevails; for the wicked surround the righteous; therefore justice comes out perverted.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="5" style="v" />“Look among the nations, watch, and wonder marvelously; for I am working a work in your days, which you will not believe though it is told you. <verse number="6" style="v" />For, behold,<note style="f" caller="+"></note> I raise up the Chaldeans, that bitter and hasty nation, that march through the width of the earth, to possess dwelling places that are not theirs. <verse number="7" style="v" />They are feared and dreaded. Their judgment and their dignity proceed from themselves. <verse number="8" style="v" />Their horses also are swifter than leopards, and are more fierce than the evening wolves. Their horsemen press proudly on. Yes, their horsemen come from afar. They fly as an eagle that hurries to devour. <verse number="9" style="v" />All of them come for violence. Their hordes face the desert. He gathers prisoners like sand. <verse number="10" style="v" />Yes, he scoffs at kings, and princes are a derision to him. He laughs at every stronghold, for he builds up an earthen ramp, and takes it. <verse number="11" style="v" />Then he sweeps by like the wind, and goes on. He is indeed guilty, whose strength is his god.”</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="12" style="v" />Aren’t you from everlasting, Yahweh my God,<note style="f" caller="+"></note> my Holy One? We will not die. Yahweh, you have appointed him for judgment. You, Rock, have established him to punish. <verse number="13" style="v" />You who have purer eyes than to see evil, and who cannot look on perversity, why do you tolerate those who deal treacherously, and keep silent when the wicked swallows up the man who is more righteous than he, <verse number="14" style="v" />and make men like the fish of the sea, like the creeping things, that have no ruler over them? <verse number="15" style="v" />He takes up all of them with the hook. He catches them in his net, and gathers them in his dragnet. Therefore he rejoices and is glad. <verse number="16" style="v" />Therefore he sacrifices to his net, and burns incense to his dragnet, because by them his life is luxurious, and his food is good. <verse number="17" style="v" />Will he therefore continually empty his net, and kill the nations without mercy?</para>
</usx>