<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="3" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Are we beginning again to commend ourselves? Or do we need, as do some, letters of commendation to you or from you? <verse number="2" style="v" />You are our letter, written in our hearts, known and read by all men; <verse number="3" style="v" />being revealed that you are a letter of Christ, served by us, written not with ink, but with the Spirit of the living God; not in tablets of stone, but in tablets that are hearts of flesh. <verse number="4" style="v" />Such confidence we have through Christ toward God; <verse number="5" style="v" />not that we are sufficient of ourselves, to account anything as from ourselves; but our sufficiency is from God; <verse number="6" style="v" />who also made us sufficient as servants of a new covenant; not of the letter, but of the Spirit. For the letter kills, but the Spirit gives life. <verse number="7" style="v" />But if the service of death, written engraved on stones, came with glory, so that the children of Israel could not look steadfastly on the face of Moses for the glory of his face, which was passing away; <verse number="8" style="v" />won’t service of the Spirit be with much more glory? <verse number="9" style="v" />For if the service of condemnation has glory, the service of righteousness exceeds much more in glory. <verse number="10" style="v" />For most certainly that which has been made glorious has not been made glorious in this respect, by reason of the glory that surpasses. <verse number="11" style="v" />For if that which passes away was with glory, much more that which remains is in glory.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="12" style="v" />Having therefore such a hope, we use great boldness of speech, <verse number="13" style="v" />and not as Moses, who put a veil on his face, that the children of Israel wouldn’t look steadfastly on the end of that which was passing away. <verse number="14" style="v" />But their minds were hardened, for until this very day at the reading of the old covenant the same veil remains, because in Christ it passes away. <verse number="15" style="v" />But to this day, when Moses is read, a veil lies on their heart. <verse number="16" style="v" />But whenever one turns to the Lord, the veil is taken away. <verse number="17" style="v" />Now the Lord is the Spirit and where the Spirit of the Lord is, there is liberty. <verse number="18" style="v" />But we all, with unveiled face seeing the glory of the Lord as in a mirror, are transformed into the same image from glory to glory, even as from the Lord, the Spirit.</para>
</usx>