<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="3" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Let not many of you be teachers, my brothers, knowing that we will receive heavier judgment. <verse number="2" style="v" />For in many things we all stumble. If anyone doesn’t stumble in word, the same is a perfect man, able to bridle the whole body also. <verse number="3" style="v" />Indeed, we put bits into the horses’ mouths so that they may obey us, and we guide their whole body. <verse number="4" style="v" />Behold,<note style="f" caller="+ “Behold”, from “ἰδοὺ”, means look at, take notice, observe, see, or gaze at. It is often used as an interjection."></note> the ships also, though they are so big and are driven by fierce winds, are yet guided by a very small rudder, wherever the pilot desires. <verse number="5" style="v" />So the tongue is also a little member, and boasts great things. See how a small fire can spread to a large forest! <verse number="6" style="v" />And the tongue is a fire. The world of iniquity among our members is the tongue, which defiles the whole body, and sets on fire the course of nature, and is set on fire by Gehenna.<note style="f" caller="+ or, Hell"></note> <verse number="7" style="v" />For every kind of animal, bird, creeping thing, and sea creature, is tamed, and has been tamed by mankind; <verse number="8" style="v" />but nobody can tame the tongue. It is a restless evil, full of deadly poison. <verse number="9" style="v" />With it we bless our God and Father, and with it we curse men, who are made in the image of God. <verse number="10" style="v" />Out of the same mouth comes blessing and cursing. My brothers, these things ought not to be so. <verse number="11" style="v" />Does a spring send out from the same opening fresh and bitter water? <verse number="12" style="v" />Can a fig tree, my brothers, yield olives, or a vine figs? Thus no spring yields both salt water and fresh water.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="13" style="v" />Who is wise and understanding among you? Let him show by his good conduct that his deeds are done in gentleness of wisdom. <verse number="14" style="v" />But if you have bitter jealousy and selfish ambition in your heart, don’t boast and don’t lie against the truth. <verse number="15" style="v" />This wisdom is not that which comes down from above, but is earthly, sensual, and demonic. <verse number="16" style="v" />For where jealousy and selfish ambition are, there is confusion and every evil deed. <verse number="17" style="v" />But the wisdom that is from above is first pure, then peaceful, gentle, reasonable, full of mercy and good fruits, without partiality, and without hypocrisy. <verse number="18" style="v" />Now the fruit of righteousness is sown in peace by those who make peace.</para>
</usx>