<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="4" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Where do wars and fightings among you come from? Don’t they come from your pleasures that war in your members? <verse number="2" style="v" />You lust, and don’t have. You murder and covet, and can’t obtain. You fight and make war. You don’t have, because you don’t ask. <verse number="3" style="v" />You ask, and don’t receive, because you ask with wrong motives, so that you may spend it on your pleasures. <verse number="4" style="v" />You adulterers and adulteresses, don’t you know that friendship with the world is hostility toward God? Whoever therefore wants to be a friend of the world makes himself an enemy of God. <verse number="5" style="v" />Or do you think that the Scripture says in vain, “The Spirit who lives in us yearns jealously”? <verse number="6" style="v" />But he gives more grace. Therefore it says, “God resists the proud, but gives grace to the humble.”<note caller="+ Proverbs 3:34" style="x"></note> <verse number="7" style="v" />Be subject therefore to God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you. <verse number="8" style="v" />Draw near to God, and he will draw near to you. Cleanse your hands, you sinners; and purify your hearts, you double-minded. <verse number="9" style="v" />Lament, mourn, and weep. Let your laughter be turned to mourning, and your joy to gloom. <verse number="10" style="v" />Humble yourselves in the sight of the Lord, and he will exalt you.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="11" style="v" />Don’t speak against one another, brothers. He who speaks against a brother and judges his brother, speaks against the law and judges the law. But if you judge the law, you are not a doer of the law, but a judge. <verse number="12" style="v" />Only one is the lawgiver, who is able to save and to destroy. But who are you to judge another?</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="13" style="v" />Come now, you who say, “Today or tomorrow let’s go into this city, and spend a year there, trade, and make a profit.” <verse number="14" style="v" />Whereas you don’t know what your life will be like tomorrow. For what is your life? For you are a vapor, that appears for a little time, and then vanishes away. <verse number="15" style="v" />For you ought to say, “If the Lord wills, we will both live, and do this or that.” <verse number="16" style="v" />But now you glory in your boasting. All such boasting is evil. <verse number="17" style="v" />To him therefore who knows to do good, and doesn’t do it, to him it is sin.</para>
</usx>