<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="24" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />After five days, the high priest, Ananias, came down with certain elders and an orator, one Tertullus. They informed the governor against Paul. <verse number="2" style="v" />When he was called, Tertullus began to accuse him, saying, “Seeing that by you we enjoy much peace, and that prosperity is coming to this nation by your foresight, <verse number="3" style="v" />we accept it in all ways and in all places, most excellent Felix, with all thankfulness. <verse number="4" style="v" />But, that I don’t delay you, I entreat you to bear with us and hear a few words. <verse number="5" style="v" />For we have found this man to be a plague, an instigator of insurrections among all the Jews throughout the world, and a ringleader of the sect of the Nazarenes. <verse number="6" style="v" />He even tried to profane the temple, and we arrested him.<note style="f" caller="+"></note> <verse number="7" style="v" /><note style="f" caller="+"></note> <verse number="8" style="v" /><note style="f" caller="+"></note>By examining him yourself you may ascertain all these things of which we accuse him.”</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="9" style="v" />The Jews also joined in the attack, affirming that these things were so. <verse number="10" style="v" />When the governor had beckoned to him to speak, Paul answered, “Because I know that you have been a judge of this nation for many years, I cheerfully make my defense, <verse number="11" style="v" />seeing that you can verify that it is not more than twelve days since I went up to worship at Jerusalem. <verse number="12" style="v" />In the temple they didn’t find me disputing with anyone or stirring up a crowd, either in the synagogues, or in the city. <verse number="13" style="v" />Nor can they prove to you the things of which they now accuse me. <verse number="14" style="v" />But this I confess to you, that after the Way, which they call a sect, so I serve the God of our fathers, believing all things which are according to the law, and which are written in the prophets; <verse number="15" style="v" />having hope toward God, which these also themselves look for, that there will be a resurrection of the dead, both of the just and unjust. <verse number="16" style="v" />Herein I also practice always having a conscience void of offense toward God and men. <verse number="17" style="v" />Now after some years, I came to bring gifts for the needy to my nation, and offerings; <verse number="18" style="v" />amid which certain Jews from Asia found me purified in the temple, not with a mob, nor with turmoil. <verse number="19" style="v" />They ought to have been here before you, and to make accusation, if they had anything against me. <verse number="20" style="v" />Or else let these men themselves say what injustice they found in me when I stood before the council, <verse number="21" style="v" />unless it is for this one thing that I cried standing among them, ‘Concerning the resurrection of the dead I am being judged before you today!’”</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="22" style="v" />But Felix, having more exact knowledge concerning the Way, deferred them, saying, “When Lysias, the commanding officer, comes down, I will decide your case.” <verse number="23" style="v" />He ordered the centurion that Paul should be kept in custody, and should have some privileges, and not to forbid any of his friends to serve him or to visit him. <verse number="24" style="v" />But after some days, Felix came with Drusilla, his wife, who was a Jewess, and sent for Paul, and heard him concerning the faith in Christ Jesus. <verse number="25" style="v" />As he reasoned about righteousness, self-control, and the judgment to come, Felix was terrified, and answered, “Go your way for this time, and when it is convenient for me, I will summon you.” <verse number="26" style="v" />Meanwhile, he also hoped that money would be given to him by Paul, that he might release him. Therefore also he sent for him more often, and talked with him. <verse number="27" style="v" />But when two years were fulfilled, Felix was succeeded by Porcius Festus, and desiring to gain favor with the Jews, Felix left Paul in bonds.</para>
</usx>