<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="25" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Yahweh spoke to Moses, saying, <verse number="2" style="v" />“Speak to the children of Israel, that they take an offering for me. From everyone whose heart makes him willing you shall take my offering. <verse number="3" style="v" />This is the offering which you shall take from them: gold, silver, brass, <verse number="4" style="v" />blue, purple, scarlet, fine linen, goats’ hair, <verse number="5" style="v" />rams’ skins dyed red, sea cow hides, acacia wood, <verse number="6" style="v" />oil for the light, spices for the anointing oil and for the sweet incense, <verse number="7" style="v" />onyx stones, and stones to be set for the ephod and for the breastplate. <verse number="8" style="v" />Let them make me a sanctuary, that I may dwell among them. <verse number="9" style="v" />According to all that I show you, the pattern of the tabernacle, and the pattern of all of its furniture, even so you shall make it.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="10" style="v" />“They shall make an ark of acacia wood. Its length shall be two and a half cubits,<note style="f" caller="+ A cubit is the length from the tip of the middle finger to the elbow on a man’s arm, or about 18 inches or 46 centimeters."></note> its width a cubit and a half, and a cubit and a half its height. <verse number="11" style="v" />You shall overlay it with pure gold. You shall overlay it inside and outside, and you shall make a gold molding around it. <verse number="12" style="v" />You shall cast four rings of gold for it, and put them in its four feet. Two rings shall be on the one side of it, and two rings on the other side of it. <verse number="13" style="v" />You shall make poles of acacia wood, and overlay them with gold. <verse number="14" style="v" />You shall put the poles into the rings on the sides of the ark to carry the ark. <verse number="15" style="v" />The poles shall be in the rings of the ark. They shall not be taken from it. <verse number="16" style="v" />You shall put the testimony which I shall give you into the ark. <verse number="17" style="v" />You shall make a mercy seat of pure gold. Two and a half cubits shall be its length, and a cubit and a half its width. <verse number="18" style="v" />You shall make two cherubim of hammered gold. You shall make them at the two ends of the mercy seat. <verse number="19" style="v" />Make one cherub at the one end, and one cherub at the other end. You shall make the cherubim on its two ends of one piece with the mercy seat. <verse number="20" style="v" />The cherubim shall spread out their wings upward, covering the mercy seat with their wings, with their faces toward one another. The faces of the cherubim shall be toward the mercy seat. <verse number="21" style="v" />You shall put the mercy seat on top of the ark, and in the ark you shall put the testimony that I will give you. <verse number="22" style="v" />There I will meet with you, and I will tell you from above the mercy seat, from between the two cherubim which are on the ark of the testimony, all that I command you for the children of Israel.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="23" style="v" />“You shall make a table of acacia wood. Two cubits shall be its length, and a cubit its width, and one and a half cubits its height. <verse number="24" style="v" />You shall overlay it with pure gold, and make a gold molding around it. <verse number="25" style="v" />You shall make a rim of a hand width around it. You shall make a golden molding on its rim around it. <verse number="26" style="v" />You shall make four rings of gold for it, and put the rings in the four corners that are on its four feet. <verse number="27" style="v" />the rings shall be close to the rim, for places for the poles to carry the table. <verse number="28" style="v" />You shall make the poles of acacia wood, and overlay them with gold, that the table may be carried with them. <verse number="29" style="v" />You shall make its dishes, its spoons, its ladles, and its bowls to pour out offerings with. You shall make them of pure gold. <verse number="30" style="v" />You shall set bread of the presence on the table before me always.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="31" style="v" />“You shall make a lamp stand of pure gold. Of hammered work shall the lamp stand be made, even its base, its shaft, its cups, its buds, and its flowers, shall be of one piece with it. <verse number="32" style="v" />There shall be six branches going out of its sides: three branches of the lamp stand out of its one side, and three branches of the lamp stand out of its other side; <verse number="33" style="v" />three cups made like almond blossoms in one branch, a bud and a flower; and three cups made like almond blossoms in the other branch, a bud and a flower, so for the six branches going out of the lamp stand; <verse number="34" style="v" />and in the lamp stand four cups made like almond blossoms, its buds and its flowers; <verse number="35" style="v" />and a bud under two branches of one piece with it, and a bud under two branches of one piece with it, and a bud under two branches of one piece with it, for the six branches going out of the lamp stand. <verse number="36" style="v" />Their buds and their branches shall be of one piece with it, all of it one beaten work of pure gold. <verse number="37" style="v" />You shall make its lamps seven, and they shall light its lamps to give light to the space in front of it. <verse number="38" style="v" />Its snuffers and its snuff dishes shall be of pure gold. <verse number="39" style="v" />It shall be made of a talent<note style="f" caller="+ A talent is about 30 kilograms or 66 pounds or 965 Troy ounces"></note> of pure gold, with all these accessories. <verse number="40" style="v" />See that you make them after their pattern, which has been shown to you on the mountain.</para>
</usx>