<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="17" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Jesus said these things, and lifting up his eyes to heaven, he said, <char style="wj">“Father, the time has come. Glorify your Son, that your Son may also glorify you; </char> <verse number="2" style="v" /><char style="wj">even as you gave him authority over all flesh, so he will give eternal life to all whom you have given him. </char> <verse number="3" style="v" /><char style="wj">This is eternal life, that they should know you, the only true God, and him whom you sent, Jesus Christ. </char> <verse number="4" style="v" /><char style="wj">I glorified you on the earth. I have accomplished the work which you have given me to do. </char> <verse number="5" style="v" /><char style="wj">Now, Father, glorify me with your own self with the glory which I had with you before the world existed. </char> <verse number="6" style="v" /><char style="wj">I revealed your name to the people whom you have given me out of the world. They were yours, and you have given them to me. They have kept your word. </char> <verse number="7" style="v" /><char style="wj">Now they have known that all things whatever you have given me are from you, </char> <verse number="8" style="v" /><char style="wj">for the words which you have given me I have given to them, and they received them, and knew for sure that I came from you, and they have believed that you sent me. </char> <verse number="9" style="v" /><char style="wj">I pray for them. I don’t pray for the world, but for those whom you have given me, for they are yours. </char> <verse number="10" style="v" /><char style="wj">All things that are mine are yours, and yours are mine, and I am glorified in them. </char> <verse number="11" style="v" /><char style="wj">I am no more in the world, but these are in the world, and I am coming to you. Holy Father, keep them through your name which you have given me, that they may be one, even as we are. </char> <verse number="12" style="v" /><char style="wj">While I was with them in the world, I kept them in your name. Those whom you have given me I have kept. None of them is lost, except the son of destruction, that the Scripture might be fulfilled. </char> <verse number="13" style="v" /><char style="wj">But now I come to you, and I say these things in the world, that they may have my joy made full in themselves. </char> <verse number="14" style="v" /><char style="wj">I have given them your word. The world hated them, because they are not of the world, even as I am not of the world. </char> <verse number="15" style="v" /><char style="wj">I pray not that you would take them from the world, but that you would keep them from the evil one. </char> <verse number="16" style="v" /><char style="wj">They are not of the world even as I am not of the world. </char> <verse number="17" style="v" /><char style="wj">Sanctify them in your truth. Your word is truth.</char><note caller="+" style="x"></note> <verse number="18" style="v" /><char style="wj">As you sent me into the world, even so I have sent them into the world. </char> <verse number="19" style="v" /><char style="wj">For their sakes I sanctify myself, that they themselves also may be sanctified in truth. </char> <verse number="20" style="v" /><char style="wj">Not for these only do I pray, but for those also who will believe in me through their word, </char> <verse number="21" style="v" /><char style="wj">that they may all be one; even as you, Father, are in me, and I in you, that they also may be one in us; that the world may believe that you sent me. </char> <verse number="22" style="v" /><char style="wj">The glory which you have given me, I have given to them; that they may be one, even as we are one; </char> <verse number="23" style="v" /><char style="wj">I in them, and you in me, that they may be perfected into one; that the world may know that you sent me, and loved them, even as you loved me. </char> <verse number="24" style="v" /><char style="wj">Father, I desire that they also whom you have given me be with me where I am, that they may see my glory, which you have given me, for you loved me before the foundation of the world. </char> <verse number="25" style="v" /><char style="wj">Righteous Father, the world hasn’t known you, but I knew you; and these knew that you sent me. </char> <verse number="26" style="v" /><char style="wj">I made known to them your name, and will make it known; that the love with which you loved me may be in them, and I in them.”</char></para>
</usx>