<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="18" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />After this, David defeated the Philistines and subdued them, and took Gath and its towns out of the hand of the Philistines. <verse number="2" style="v" />He defeated Moab; and the Moabites became servants to David, and brought tribute. <verse number="3" style="v" />David defeated Hadadezer king of Zobah to Hamath, as he went to establish his dominion by the river Euphrates. <verse number="4" style="v" />David took from him one thousand chariots, seven thousand horsemen, and twenty thousand footmen; and David hamstrung all the chariot horses, but reserved of them enough for one hundred chariots. <verse number="5" style="v" />When the Syrians of Damascus came to help Hadadezer king of Zobah, David struck twenty-two thousand men of the Syrians. <verse number="6" style="v" />Then David put garrisons in Syria of Damascus; and the Syrians became servants to David, and brought tribute. Yahweh gave victory to David wherever he went. <verse number="7" style="v" />David took the shields of gold that were on the servants of Hadadezer, and brought them to Jerusalem. <verse number="8" style="v" />From Tibhath and from Cun, cities of Hadadezer, David took very much brass, with which Solomon made the bronze sea, the pillars, and the vessels of brass.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="9" style="v" />When Tou king of Hamath heard that David had struck all the army of Hadadezer king of Zobah, <verse number="10" style="v" />he sent Hadoram his son to king David, to Greet him, and to bless him, because he had fought against Hadadezer and struck him (for Hadadezer had wars with Tou); and he had with him all kinds of vessels of gold and silver and brass. <verse number="11" style="v" />King David also dedicated these to Yahweh, with the silver and the gold that he carried away from all the nations; from Edom, from Moab, from the children of Ammon, from the Philistines, and from Amalek. <verse number="12" style="v" />Moreover Abishai the son of Zeruiah struck eighteen thousand of the Edomites in the Valley of Salt. <verse number="13" style="v" />He put garrisons in Edom; and all the Edomites became servants to David. Yahweh gave victory to David wherever he went.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="14" style="v" />David reigned over all Israel; and he executed justice and righteousness for all his people. <verse number="15" style="v" />Joab the son of Zeruiah was over the army; Jehoshaphat the son of Ahilud was recorder; <verse number="16" style="v" />Zadok the son of Ahitub, and Abimelech the son of Abiathar, were priests; Shavsha was scribe; <verse number="17" style="v" />and Benaiah the son of Jehoiada was over the Cherethites and the Pelethites; and the sons of David were chief officials serving the king.</para>
</usx>