<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="24" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />These were the divisions of the sons of Aaron. The sons of Aaron: Nadab, Abihu, Eleazar, and Ithamar. <verse number="2" style="v" />But Nadab and Abihu died before their father, and had no children: therefore Eleazar and Ithamar executed the priest’s office. <verse number="3" style="v" />David with Zadok of the sons of Eleazar and Ahimelech of the sons of Ithamar, divided them according to their ordering in their service. <verse number="4" style="v" />There were more chief men found of the sons of Eleazar than of the sons of Ithamar; and they were divided like this: of the sons of Eleazar there were sixteen, heads of fathers’ houses; and of the sons of Ithamar, according to their fathers’ houses, eight. <verse number="5" style="v" />Thus were they divided impartially by drawing lots; for there were princes of the sanctuary, and princes of God, both of the sons of Eleazar, and of the sons of Ithamar. <verse number="6" style="v" />Shemaiah the son of Nethanel the scribe, who was of the Levites, wrote them in the presence of the king, the princes, Zadok the priest, Ahimelech the son of Abiathar, and the heads of the fathers’ households of the priests and of the Levites; one fathers’ house being taken for Eleazar, and one taken for Ithamar. <verse number="7" style="v" />Now the first lot came out to Jehoiarib, the second to Jedaiah, <verse number="8" style="v" />the third to Harim, the fourth to Seorim, <verse number="9" style="v" />the fifth to Malchijah, the sixth to Mijamin, <verse number="10" style="v" />the seventh to Hakkoz, the eighth to Abijah, <verse number="11" style="v" />the ninth to Jeshua, the tenth to Shecaniah, <verse number="12" style="v" />the eleventh to Eliashib, the twelfth to Jakim, <verse number="13" style="v" />the thirteenth to Huppah, the fourteenth to Jeshebeab, <verse number="14" style="v" />the fifteenth to Bilgah, the sixteenth to Immer, <verse number="15" style="v" />the seventeenth to Hezir, the eighteenth to Happizzez, <verse number="16" style="v" />the nineteenth to Pethahiah, the twentieth to Jehezkel, <verse number="17" style="v" />the twenty-first to Jachin, the twenty-second to Gamul, <verse number="18" style="v" />the twenty-third to Delaiah, and the twenty-fourth to Maaziah. <verse number="19" style="v" />This was their ordering in their service, to come into Yahweh’s house according to the ordinance given to them by Aaron their father, as Yahweh, the God of Israel, had commanded him.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="20" style="v" />Of the rest of the sons of Levi: of the sons of Amram, Shubael; of the sons of Shubael, Jehdeiah. <verse number="21" style="v" />Of Rehabiah: of the sons of Rehabiah, Isshiah the chief. <verse number="22" style="v" />Of the Izharites, Shelomoth; of the sons of Shelomoth, Jahath. <verse number="23" style="v" />The sons of Hebron: Jeriah, Amariah the second, Jahaziel the third, and Jekameam the fourth. <verse number="24" style="v" />The sons of Uzziel: Micah; of the sons of Micah, Shamir. <verse number="25" style="v" />The brother of Micah: Isshiah; of the sons of Isshiah, Zechariah. <verse number="26" style="v" />The sons of Merari: Mahli and Mushi. The son of Jaaziah: Beno. <verse number="27" style="v" />The sons of Merari: of Jaaziah, Beno, Shoham, Zaccur, and Ibri. <verse number="28" style="v" />Of Mahli: Eleazar, who had no sons. <verse number="29" style="v" />Of Kish, the son of Kish: Jerahmeel. <verse number="30" style="v" />The sons of Mushi: Mahli, Eder, and Jerimoth. These were the sons of the Levites after their fathers’ houses. <verse number="31" style="v" />These likewise cast lots even as their brothers the sons of Aaron in the presence of David the king, Zadok, Ahimelech, and the heads of the fathers’ households of the priests and of the Levites; the fathers’ households of the chief even as those of his younger brother.</para>
</usx>