<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="3" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Now these were the sons of David, who were born to him in Hebron: the firstborn, Amnon, of Ahinoam the Jezreelitess; the second, Daniel, of Abigail the Carmelitess; <verse number="2" style="v" />the third, Absalom the son of Maacah the daughter of Talmai king of Geshur; the fourth, Adonijah the son of Haggith; <verse number="3" style="v" />the fifth, Shephatiah of Abital; the sixth, Ithream by Eglah his wife: <verse number="4" style="v" />six were born to him in Hebron; and he reigned there seven years and six months. He reigned thirty-three years in Jerusalem; <verse number="5" style="v" />and these were born to him in Jerusalem: Shimea, Shobab, Nathan, and Solomon, four, of Bathshua the daughter of Ammiel; <verse number="6" style="v" />and Ibhar, Elishama, Eliphelet, <verse number="7" style="v" />Nogah, Nepheg, Japhia, <verse number="8" style="v" />Elishama, Eliada, and Eliphelet, nine. <verse number="9" style="v" />All these were the sons of David, besides the sons of the concubines; and Tamar was their sister.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="10" style="v" />Solomon’s son was Rehoboam, Abijah his son, Asa his son, Jehoshaphat his son, <verse number="11" style="v" />Joram his son, Ahaziah his son, Joash his son, <verse number="12" style="v" />Amaziah his son, Azariah his son, Jotham his son, <verse number="13" style="v" />Ahaz his son, Hezekiah his son, Manasseh his son, <verse number="14" style="v" />Amon his son, and Josiah his son. <verse number="15" style="v" />The sons of Josiah: the firstborn Johanan, the second Jehoiakim, the third Zedekiah, and the fourth Shallum. <verse number="16" style="v" />The sons of Jehoiakim: Jeconiah his son, and Zedekiah his son. <verse number="17" style="v" />The sons of Jeconiah, the captive: Shealtiel his son, <verse number="18" style="v" />Malchiram, Pedaiah, Shenazzar, Jekamiah, Hoshama, and Nedabiah. <verse number="19" style="v" />The sons of Pedaiah: Zerubbabel and Shimei. The sons of Zerubbabel: Meshullam and Hananiah; and Shelomith was their sister; <verse number="20" style="v" />and Hashubah, Ohel, Berechiah, Hasadiah, and Jushab Hesed, five. <verse number="21" style="v" />The sons of Hananiah: Pelatiah and Jeshaiah; the sons of Rephaiah, the sons of Arnan, the sons of Obadiah, the sons of Shecaniah. <verse number="22" style="v" />The son of Shecaniah: Shemaiah. The sons of Shemaiah: Hattush, Igal, Bariah, Neariah, and Shaphat, six. <verse number="23" style="v" />The sons of Neariah: Elioenai, Hizkiah, and Azrikam, three. <verse number="24" style="v" />The sons of Elioenai: Hodaviah, Eliashib, Pelaiah, Akkub, Johanan, Delaiah, and Anani, seven.</para>
</usx>