<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="6" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />The sons of Levi: Gershon, Kohath, and Merari. <verse number="2" style="v" />The sons of Kohath: Amram, Izhar, and Hebron, and Uzziel. <verse number="3" style="v" />The children of Amram: Aaron, Moses, and Miriam. The sons of Aaron: Nadab, Abihu, Eleazar, and Ithamar. <verse number="4" style="v" />Eleazar became the father of Phinehas, Phinehas became the father of Abishua, <verse number="5" style="v" />Abishua became the father of Bukki. Bukki became the father of Uzzi. <verse number="6" style="v" />Uzzi became the father of Zerahiah. Zerahiah became the father of Meraioth. <verse number="7" style="v" />Meraioth became the father of Amariah. Amariah became the father of Ahitub. <verse number="8" style="v" />Ahitub became the father of Zadok. Zadok became the father of Ahimaaz. <verse number="9" style="v" />Ahimaaz became the father of Azariah. Azariah became the father of Johanan. <verse number="10" style="v" />Johanan became the father of Azariah, who executed the priest’s office in the house that Solomon built in Jerusalem. <verse number="11" style="v" />Azariah became the father of Amariah. Amariah became the father of Ahitub. <verse number="12" style="v" />Ahitub became the father of Zadok. Zadok became the father of Shallum. <verse number="13" style="v" />Shallum became the father of Hilkiah. Hilkiah became the father of Azariah. <verse number="14" style="v" />Azariah became the father of Seraiah. Seraiah became the father of Jehozadak. <verse number="15" style="v" />Jehozadak went into captivity, when Yahweh carried Judah and Jerusalem away by the hand of Nebuchadnezzar.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="16" style="v" />The sons of Levi: Gershom, Kohath, and Merari. <verse number="17" style="v" />These are the names of the sons of Gershom: Libni and Shimei. <verse number="18" style="v" />The sons of Kohath were Amram, Izhar, Hebron, and Uzziel. <verse number="19" style="v" />The sons of Merari: Mahli and Mushi. These are the families of the Levites according to their fathers’ households. <verse number="20" style="v" />Of Gershom: Libni his son, Jahath his son, Zimmah his son, <verse number="21" style="v" />Joah his son, Iddo his son, Zerah his son, and Jeatherai his son. <verse number="22" style="v" />The sons of Kohath: Amminadab his son, Korah his son, Assir his son, <verse number="23" style="v" />Elkanah his son, and Ebiasaph his son, Assir his son, <verse number="24" style="v" />Tahath his son, Uriel his son, Uzziah his son, and Shaul his son. <verse number="25" style="v" />The sons of Elkanah: Amasai and Ahimoth. <verse number="26" style="v" />As for Elkanah, the sons of Elkanah: Zophai his son, Nahath his son, <verse number="27" style="v" />Eliab his son, Jeroham his son, and Elkanah his son. <verse number="28" style="v" />The sons of Samuel: the firstborn, Joel, and the second, Abijah. <verse number="29" style="v" />The sons of Merari: Mahli, Libni his son, Shimei his son, Uzzah his son, <verse number="30" style="v" />Shimea his son, Haggiah his son, Asaiah his son. <verse number="31" style="v" />These are they whom David set over the service of song in Yahweh’s house, after the ark came to rest there. <verse number="32" style="v" />They ministered with song before the tabernacle of the Tent of Meeting, until Solomon had built Yahweh’s house in Jerusalem. They performed the duties of their office according to their order. <verse number="33" style="v" />These are those who served, and their sons. Of the sons of the Kohathites: Heman the singer, the son of Joel, the son of Samuel, <verse number="34" style="v" />the son of Elkanah, the son of Jeroham, the son of Eliel, the son of Toah, <verse number="35" style="v" />the son of Zuph, the son of Elkanah, the son of Mahath, the son of Amasai, <verse number="36" style="v" />the son of Elkanah, the son of Joel, the son of Azariah, the son of Zephaniah, <verse number="37" style="v" />the son of Tahath, the son of Assir, the son of Ebiasaph, the son of Korah, <verse number="38" style="v" />the son of Izhar, the son of Kohath, the son of Levi, the son of Israel. <verse number="39" style="v" />His brother Asaph, who stood on his right hand, even Asaph the son of Berechiah, the son of Shimea, <verse number="40" style="v" />the son of Michael, the son of Baaseiah, the son of Malchijah, <verse number="41" style="v" />the son of Ethni, the son of Zerah, the son of Adaiah, <verse number="42" style="v" />the son of Ethan, the son of Zimmah, the son of Shimei, <verse number="43" style="v" />the son of Jahath, the son of Gershom, the son of Levi. <verse number="44" style="v" />On the left hand their brothers the sons of Merari: Ethan the son of Kishi, the son of Abdi, the son of Malluch, <verse number="45" style="v" />the son of Hashabiah, the son of Amaziah, the son of Hilkiah, <verse number="46" style="v" />the son of Amzi, the son of Bani, the son of Shemer, <verse number="47" style="v" />the son of Mahli, the son of Mushi, the son of Merari, the son of Levi. <verse number="48" style="v" />Their brothers the Levites were appointed for all the service of the tabernacle of God’s house. <verse number="49" style="v" />But Aaron and his sons offered on the altar of burnt offering, and on the altar of incense, for all the work of the most holy place, and to make atonement for Israel, according to all that Moses the servant of God had commanded.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="50" style="v" />These are the sons of Aaron: Eleazar his son, Phinehas his son, Abishua his son, <verse number="51" style="v" />Bukki his son, Uzzi his son, Zerahiah his son, <verse number="52" style="v" />Meraioth his son, Amariah his son, Ahitub his son, <verse number="53" style="v" />Zadok his son, and Ahimaaz his son. <verse number="54" style="v" />Now these are their dwelling places according to their encampments in their borders: to the sons of Aaron, of the families of the Kohathites (for theirs was the first lot), <verse number="55" style="v" />to them they gave Hebron in the land of Judah, and its suburbs around it; <verse number="56" style="v" />but the fields of the city, and its villages, they gave to Caleb the son of Jephunneh. <verse number="57" style="v" />To the sons of Aaron they gave the cities of refuge, Hebron; Libnah also with its suburbs, Jattir, Eshtemoa with its suburbs, <verse number="58" style="v" />Hilen with its suburbs, Debir with its suburbs, <verse number="59" style="v" />Ashan with its suburbs, and Beth Shemesh with its suburbs; <verse number="60" style="v" />and out of the tribe of Benjamin, Geba with its suburbs, Allemeth with its suburbs, and Anathoth with its suburbs. All their cities throughout their families were thirteen cities.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="61" style="v" />To the rest of the sons of Kohath were given by lot, out of the family of the tribe, out of the half-tribe, the half of Manasseh, ten cities. <verse number="62" style="v" />To the sons of Gershom, according to their families, out of the tribe of Issachar, and out of the tribe of Asher, and out of the tribe of Naphtali, and out of the tribe of Manasseh in Bashan, thirteen cities. <verse number="63" style="v" />To the sons of Merari were given by lot, according to their families, out of the tribe of Reuben, and out of the tribe of Gad, and out of the tribe of Zebulun, twelve cities. <verse number="64" style="v" />The children of Israel gave to the Levites the cities with their suburbs. <verse number="65" style="v" />They gave by lot out of the tribe of the children of Judah, and out of the tribe of the children of Simeon, and out of the tribe of the children of Benjamin, these cities which are mentioned by name. <verse number="66" style="v" />Some of the families of the sons of Kohath had cities of their borders out of the tribe of Ephraim. <verse number="67" style="v" />They gave to them the cities of refuge, Shechem in the hill country of Ephraim with its suburbs; Gezer also with its suburbs, <verse number="68" style="v" />Jokmeam with its suburbs, Beth Horon with its suburbs, <verse number="69" style="v" />Aijalon with its suburbs, Gath Rimmon with its suburbs; <verse number="70" style="v" />and out of the half-tribe of Manasseh, Aner with its suburbs, and Bileam with its suburbs, for the rest of the family of the sons of Kohath.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="71" style="v" />To the sons of Gershom were given, out of the family of the half-tribe of Manasseh, Golan in Bashan with its suburbs, and Ashtaroth with its suburbs; <verse number="72" style="v" />and out of the tribe of Issachar, Kedesh with its suburbs, Daberath with its suburbs, <verse number="73" style="v" />Ramoth with its suburbs, and Anem with its suburbs; <verse number="74" style="v" />and out of the tribe of Asher, Mashal with its suburbs, Abdon with its suburbs, <verse number="75" style="v" />Hukok with its suburbs, and Rehob with its suburbs; <verse number="76" style="v" />and out of the tribe of Naphtali, Kedesh in Galilee with its suburbs, Hammon with its suburbs, and Kiriathaim with its suburbs.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="77" style="v" />To the rest of the Levites, the sons of Merari, were given, out of the tribe of Zebulun, Rimmono with its suburbs, Tabor with its suburbs; <verse number="78" style="v" />and beyond the Jordan at Jericho, on the east side of the Jordan, were given them, out of the tribe of Reuben, Bezer in the wilderness with its suburbs, and Jahzah with its suburbs, <verse number="79" style="v" />Kedemoth with its suburbs, and Mephaath with its suburbs; <verse number="80" style="v" />and out of the tribe of Gad, Ramoth in Gilead with its suburbs, Mahanaim with its suburbs, <verse number="81" style="v" />Heshbon with its suburbs, and Jazer with its suburbs.</para>
</usx>