<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="8" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Benjamin became the father of Bela his firstborn, Ashbel the second, Aharah the third, <verse number="2" style="v" />Nohah the fourth, and Rapha the fifth. <verse number="3" style="v" />Bela had sons: Addar, Gera, Abihud, <verse number="4" style="v" />Abishua, Naaman, Ahoah, <verse number="5" style="v" />Gera, Shephuphan, and Huram. <verse number="6" style="v" />These are the sons of Ehud. These are the heads of fathers’ households of the inhabitants of Geba, who were carried captive to Manahath: <verse number="7" style="v" />Naaman, Ahijah, and Gera, who carried them captive; and he became the father of Uzza and Ahihud.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="8" style="v" />Shaharaim became the father of children in the field of Moab, after he had sent them away. Hushim and Baara were his wives. <verse number="9" style="v" />By Hodesh his wife, he became the father of Jobab, Zibia, Mesha, Malcam, <verse number="10" style="v" />Jeuz, Shachia, and Mirmah. These were his sons, heads of fathers’ households. <verse number="11" style="v" />By Hushim, he became the father of Abitub and Elpaal. <verse number="12" style="v" />The sons of Elpaal: Eber, Misham, and Shemed, who built Ono and Lod, with its towns; <verse number="13" style="v" />and Beriah, and Shema, who were heads of fathers’ households of the inhabitants of Aijalon, who put to flight the inhabitants of Gath; <verse number="14" style="v" />and Ahio, Shashak, Jeremoth, <verse number="15" style="v" />Zebadiah, Arad, Eder, <verse number="16" style="v" />Michael, Ishpah, Joha, the sons of Beriah, <verse number="17" style="v" />Zebadiah, Meshullam, Hizki, Heber, <verse number="18" style="v" />Ishmerai, Izliah, Jobab, the sons of Elpaal, <verse number="19" style="v" />Jakim, Zichri, Zabdi, <verse number="20" style="v" />Elienai, Zillethai, Eliel, <verse number="21" style="v" />Adaiah, Beraiah, Shimrath, the sons of Shimei, <verse number="22" style="v" />Ishpan, Eber, Eliel, <verse number="23" style="v" />Abdon, Zichri, Hanan, <verse number="24" style="v" />Hananiah, Elam, Anthothijah, <verse number="25" style="v" />Iphdeiah, Penuel, the sons of Shashak, <verse number="26" style="v" />Shamsherai, Shehariah, Athaliah, <verse number="27" style="v" />Jaareshiah, Elijah, Zichri, and the sons of Jeroham. <verse number="28" style="v" />These were heads of fathers’ households throughout their generations, chief men. These lived in Jerusalem. <verse number="29" style="v" />The father of Gibeon, whose wife’s name was Maacah, lived in Gibeon, <verse number="30" style="v" />with his firstborn son Abdon, Zur, Kish, Baal, Nadab, <verse number="31" style="v" />Gedor, Ahio, and Zecher. <verse number="32" style="v" />Mikloth became the father of Shimeah. They also lived with their brothers in Jerusalem, near their brothers. <verse number="33" style="v" />Ner became the father of Kish. Kish became the father of Saul. Saul became the father of Jonathan, Malchishua, Abinadab, and Eshbaal. <verse number="34" style="v" />The son of Jonathan was Merib Baal. Merib Baal became the father of Micah. <verse number="35" style="v" />The sons of Micah: Pithon, Melech, Tarea, and Ahaz. <verse number="36" style="v" />Ahaz became the father of Jehoaddah. Jehoaddah became the father of Alemeth, Azmaveth, and Zimri. Zimri became the father of Moza. <verse number="37" style="v" />Moza became the father of Binea. Raphah was his son, Eleasah his son, and Azel his son. <verse number="38" style="v" />Azel had six sons, whose names are these: Azrikam, Bocheru, Ishmael, Sheariah, Obadiah, and Hanan. All these were the sons of Azel. <verse number="39" style="v" />The sons of Eshek his brother: Ulam his firstborn, Jeush the second, and Eliphelet the third. <verse number="40" style="v" />The sons of Ulam were mighty men of valor, archers, and had many sons, and sons’ sons, one hundred fifty. All these were of the sons of Benjamin.</para>
</usx>