<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="17" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Jehoshaphat his son reigned in his place, and strengthened himself against Israel. <verse number="2" style="v" />He placed forces in all the fortified cities of Judah, and set garrisons in the land of Judah, and in the cities of Ephraim, which Asa his father had taken. <verse number="3" style="v" />Yahweh was with Jehoshaphat, because he walked in the first ways of his father David, and didn’t seek the Baals, <verse number="4" style="v" />but sought to the God of his father, and walked in his commandments, and not in the ways of Israel. <verse number="5" style="v" />Therefore Yahweh established the kingdom in his hand. All Judah brought tribute to Jehoshaphat, and he had riches and honor in abundance. <verse number="6" style="v" />His heart was lifted up in the ways of Yahweh. Furthermore, he took away the high places and the Asherah poles out of Judah. <verse number="7" style="v" />Also in the third year of his reign he sent his princes, even Ben Hail, Obadiah, Zechariah, Nethanel, and Micaiah, to teach in the cities of Judah; <verse number="8" style="v" />and with them the Levites, even Shemaiah, Nethaniah, Zebadiah, Asahel, Shemiramoth, Jehonathan, Adonijah, Tobijah, and Tobadonijah, the Levites; and with them Elishama and Jehoram, the priests. <verse number="9" style="v" />They taught in Judah, having the book of Yahweh’s law with them. They went about throughout all the cities of Judah and taught among the people. <verse number="10" style="v" />The fear of Yahweh fell on all the kingdoms of the lands that were around Judah, so that they made no war against Jehoshaphat. <verse number="11" style="v" />Some of the Philistines brought Jehoshaphat presents and silver for tribute. The Arabians also brought him flocks, seven thousand seven hundred rams, and seven thousand seven hundred male goats. <verse number="12" style="v" />Jehoshaphat grew great exceedingly; and he built fortresses and store cities in Judah. <verse number="13" style="v" />He had many works in the cities of Judah; and men of war, mighty men of valor, in Jerusalem. <verse number="14" style="v" />This was the numbering of them according to their fathers’ houses: From Judah, the captains of thousands: Adnah the captain, and with him three hundred thousand mighty men of valor; <verse number="15" style="v" />and next to him Jehohanan the captain, and with him two hundred eighty thousand; <verse number="16" style="v" />and next to him Amasiah the son of Zichri, who willingly offered himself to Yahweh, and with him two hundred thousand mighty men of valor. <verse number="17" style="v" />From Benjamin: Eliada, a mighty man of valor, and with him two hundred thousand armed with bow and shield; <verse number="18" style="v" />and next to him Jehozabad, and with him one hundred eighty thousand ready and prepared for war. <verse number="19" style="v" />These were those who waited on the king, besides those whom the king put in the fortified cities throughout all Judah.</para>
</usx>