<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="1" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Paul, an apostle of Christ Jesus through the will of God, to the saints who are at Ephesus, and the faithful in Christ Jesus: <verse number="2" style="v" />Grace to you and peace from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="3" style="v" />Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places in Christ; <verse number="4" style="v" />even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we would be holy and without defect before him in love; <verse number="5" style="v" />having predestined us for adoption as children through Jesus Christ to himself, according to the good pleasure of his desire, <verse number="6" style="v" />to the praise of the glory of his grace, by which he freely gave us favor in the Beloved, <verse number="7" style="v" />in whom we have our redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of our trespasses, according to the riches of his grace, <verse number="8" style="v" />which he made to abound toward us in all wisdom and prudence, <verse number="9" style="v" />making known to us the mystery of his will, according to his good pleasure which he purposed in him <verse number="10" style="v" />to an administration of the fullness of the times, to sum up all things in Christ, the things in the heavens, and the things on the earth, in him; <verse number="11" style="v" />in whom also we were assigned an inheritance, having been foreordained according to the purpose of him who does all things after the counsel of his will; <verse number="12" style="v" />to the end that we should be to the praise of his glory, we who had before hoped in Christ. <verse number="13" style="v" />In him you also, having heard the word of the truth, the Good News of your salvation—in whom, having also believed, you were sealed with the promised Holy Spirit, <verse number="14" style="v" />who is a pledge of our inheritance, to the redemption of God’s own possession, to the praise of his glory. <verse number="15" style="v" />For this cause I also, having heard of the faith in the Lord Jesus which is among you, and the love which you have toward all the saints, <verse number="16" style="v" />don’t cease to give thanks for you, making mention of you in my prayers, <verse number="17" style="v" />that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of glory, may give to you a spirit of wisdom and revelation in the knowledge of him; <verse number="18" style="v" />having the eyes of your hearts<note style="f" caller="+"></note> enlightened, that you may know what is the hope of his calling, and what are the riches of the glory of his inheritance in the saints, <verse number="19" style="v" />and what is the exceeding greatness of his power toward us who believe, according to that working of the strength of his might <verse number="20" style="v" />which he worked in Christ, when he raised him from the dead, and made him to sit at his right hand in the heavenly places, <verse number="21" style="v" />far above all rule, and authority, and power, and dominion, and every name that is named, not only in this age, but also in that which is to come. <verse number="22" style="v" />He put all things in subjection under his feet, and gave him to be head over all things for the assembly, <verse number="23" style="v" />which is his body, the fullness of him who fills all in all.</para>
</usx>