<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="2" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />You were made alive when you were dead in transgressions and sins, <verse number="2" style="v" />in which you once walked according to the course of this world, according to the prince of the power of the air, the spirit who now works in the children of disobedience; <verse number="3" style="v" />among whom we also all once lived in the lusts of our flesh, doing the desires of the flesh and of the mind, and were by nature children of wrath, even as the rest. <verse number="4" style="v" />But God, being rich in mercy, for his great love with which he loved us, <verse number="5" style="v" />even when we were dead through our trespasses, made us alive together with Christ (by grace you have been saved), <verse number="6" style="v" />and raised us up with him, and made us to sit with him in the heavenly places in Christ Jesus, <verse number="7" style="v" />that in the ages to come he might show the exceeding riches of his grace in kindness toward us in Christ Jesus; <verse number="8" style="v" />for by grace you have been saved through faith, and that not of yourselves; it is the gift of God, <verse number="9" style="v" />not of works, that no one would boast. <verse number="10" style="v" />For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared before that we would walk in them.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="11" style="v" />Therefore remember that once you, the Gentiles in the flesh, who are called “uncircumcision” by that which is called “circumcision”, (in the flesh, made by hands); <verse number="12" style="v" />that you were at that time separate from Christ, alienated from the commonwealth of Israel, and strangers from the covenants of the promise, having no hope and without God in the world. <verse number="13" style="v" />But now in Christ Jesus you who once were far off are made near in the blood of Christ. <verse number="14" style="v" />For he is our peace, who made both one, and broke down the middle wall of partition, <verse number="15" style="v" />having abolished in his flesh the hostility, the law of commandments contained in ordinances, that he might create in himself one new man of the two, making peace; <verse number="16" style="v" />and might reconcile them both in one body to God through the cross, having killed the hostility thereby. <verse number="17" style="v" />He came and preached peace to you who were far off and to those who were near. <verse number="18" style="v" />For through him we both have our access in one Spirit to the Father. <verse number="19" style="v" />So then you are no longer strangers and foreigners, but you are fellow citizens with the saints, and of the household of God, <verse number="20" style="v" />being built on the foundation of the apostles and prophets, Christ Jesus himself being the chief cornerstone; <verse number="21" style="v" />in whom the whole building, fitted together, grows into a holy temple in the Lord; <verse number="22" style="v" />in whom you also are built together for a habitation of God in the Spirit.</para>
</usx>