<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="1" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Paul, a servant of God, and an apostle of Jesus Christ, according to the faith of God’s chosen ones, and the knowledge of the truth which is according to godliness, <verse number="2" style="v" />in hope of eternal life, which God, who can’t lie, promised before time began; <verse number="3" style="v" />but in his own time revealed his word in the message with which I was entrusted according to the commandment of God our Savior; <verse number="4" style="v" />to Titus, my true child according to a common faith: Grace, mercy, and peace from God the Father and the Lord Jesus Christ our Savior.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="5" style="v" />I left you in Crete for this reason, that you would set in order the things that were lacking, and appoint elders in every city, as I directed you; <verse number="6" style="v" />if anyone is blameless, the husband of one wife, having children who believe, who are not accused of loose or unruly behavior. <verse number="7" style="v" />For the overseer must be blameless, as God’s steward; not self-pleasing, not easily angered, not given to wine, not violent, not greedy for dishonest gain; <verse number="8" style="v" />but given to hospitality, a lover of good, sober minded, fair, holy, self-controlled; <verse number="9" style="v" />holding to the faithful word which is according to the teaching, that he may be able to exhort in the sound doctrine, and to convict those who contradict him. <verse number="10" style="v" />For there are also many unruly men, vain talkers and deceivers, especially those of the circumcision, <verse number="11" style="v" />whose mouths must be stopped; men who overthrow whole houses, teaching things which they ought not, for dishonest gain’s sake. <verse number="12" style="v" />One of them, a prophet of their own, said, “Cretans are always liars, evil beasts, and idle gluttons.” <verse number="13" style="v" />This testimony is true. For this cause, reprove them sharply, that they may be sound in the faith, <verse number="14" style="v" />not paying attention to Jewish fables and commandments of men who turn away from the truth. <verse number="15" style="v" />To the pure, all things are pure; but to those who are defiled and unbelieving, nothing is pure; but both their mind and their conscience are defiled. <verse number="16" style="v" />They profess that they know God, but by their deeds they deny him, being abominable, disobedient, and unfit for any good work.</para>
</usx>