<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="2" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Therefore you are without excuse, O man, whoever you are who judge. For in that which you judge another, you condemn yourself. For you who judge practice the same things. <verse number="2" style="v" />We know that the judgment of God is according to truth against those who practice such things. <verse number="3" style="v" />Do you think this, O man who judges those who practice such things, and do the same, that you will escape the judgment of God? <verse number="4" style="v" />Or do you despise the riches of his goodness, forbearance, and patience, not knowing that the goodness of God leads you to repentance? <verse number="5" style="v" />But according to your hardness and unrepentant heart you are treasuring up for yourself wrath in the day of wrath, revelation, and of the righteous judgment of God; <verse number="6" style="v" />who “will pay back to everyone according to their works:”<note caller="+" style="x"></note> <verse number="7" style="v" />to those who by perseverance in well-doing seek for glory, honor, and incorruptibility, eternal life; <verse number="8" style="v" />but to those who are self-seeking, and don’t obey the truth, but obey unrighteousness, will be wrath and indignation, <verse number="9" style="v" />oppression and anguish, on every soul of man who does evil, to the Jew first, and also to the Greek.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="10" style="v" />But glory, honor, and peace go to every man who does good, to the Jew first, and also to the Greek. <verse number="11" style="v" />For there is no partiality with God. <verse number="12" style="v" />For as many as have sinned without law will also perish without the law. As many as have sinned under the law will be judged by the law. <verse number="13" style="v" />For it isn’t the hearers of the law who are righteous before God, but the doers of the law will be justified <verse number="14" style="v" />(for when Gentiles who don’t have the law do by nature the things of the law, these, not having the law, are a law to themselves, <verse number="15" style="v" />in that they show the work of the law written in their hearts, their conscience testifying with them, and their thoughts among themselves accusing or else excusing them) <verse number="16" style="v" />in the day when God will judge the secrets of men, according to my Good News, by Jesus Christ.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="17" style="v" />Indeed you bear the name of a Jew, and rest on the law, and glory in God, <verse number="18" style="v" />and know his will, and approve the things that are excellent, being instructed out of the law, <verse number="19" style="v" />and are confident that you yourself are a guide of the blind, a light to those who are in darkness, <verse number="20" style="v" />a corrector of the foolish, a teacher of babies, having in the law the form of knowledge and of the truth. <verse number="21" style="v" />You therefore who teach another, don’t you teach yourself? You who preach that a man shouldn’t steal, do you steal? <verse number="22" style="v" />You who say a man shouldn’t commit adultery. Do you commit adultery? You who abhor idols, do you rob temples? <verse number="23" style="v" />You who glory in the law, do you dishonor God by disobeying the law? <verse number="24" style="v" />For “the name of God is blasphemed among the Gentiles because of you,” <note caller="+" style="x"></note> just as it is written. <verse number="25" style="v" />For circumcision indeed profits, if you are a doer of the law, but if you are a transgressor of the law, your circumcision has become uncircumcision. <verse number="26" style="v" />If therefore the uncircumcised keep the ordinances of the law, won’t his uncircumcision be accounted as circumcision? <verse number="27" style="v" />Won’t the uncircumcision which is by nature, if it fulfills the law, judge you, who with the letter and circumcision are a transgressor of the law? <verse number="28" style="v" />For he is not a Jew who is one outwardly, neither is that circumcision which is outward in the flesh; <verse number="29" style="v" />but he is a Jew who is one inwardly, and circumcision is that of the heart, in the spirit not in the letter; whose praise is not from men, but from God.</para>
</usx>