<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="5" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Stand firm therefore in the liberty by which Christ has made us free, and don’t be entangled again with a yoke of bondage. <verse number="2" style="v" />Behold, I, Paul, tell you that if you receive circumcision, Christ will profit you nothing. <verse number="3" style="v" />Yes, I testify again to every man who receives circumcision, that he is a debtor to do the whole law. <verse number="4" style="v" />You are alienated from Christ, you who desire to be justified by the law. You have fallen away from grace. <verse number="5" style="v" />For we, through the Spirit, by faith wait for the hope of righteousness. <verse number="6" style="v" />For in Christ Jesus neither circumcision amounts to anything, nor uncircumcision, but faith working through love. <verse number="7" style="v" />You were running well! Who interfered with you that you should not obey the truth? <verse number="8" style="v" />This persuasion is not from him who calls you. <verse number="9" style="v" />A little yeast grows through the whole lump. <verse number="10" style="v" />I have confidence toward you in the Lord that you will think no other way. But he who troubles you will bear his judgment, whoever he is.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="11" style="v" />But I, brothers, if I still preach circumcision, why am I still persecuted? Then the stumbling block of the cross has been removed. <verse number="12" style="v" />I wish that those who disturb you would cut themselves off. <verse number="13" style="v" />For you, brothers, were called for freedom. Only don’t use your freedom for gain to the flesh, but through love be servants to one another. <verse number="14" style="v" />For the whole law is fulfilled in one word, in this: “You shall love your neighbor as yourself.”<note caller="+" style="x"></note> <verse number="15" style="v" />But if you bite and devour one another, be careful that you don’t consume one another. <verse number="16" style="v" />But I say, walk by the Spirit, and you won’t fulfill the lust of the flesh. <verse number="17" style="v" />For the flesh lusts against the Spirit, and the Spirit against the flesh; and these are contrary to one another, that you may not do the things that you desire. <verse number="18" style="v" />But if you are led by the Spirit, you are not under the law. <verse number="19" style="v" />Now the deeds of the flesh are obvious, which are: adultery, sexual immorality, uncleanness, lustfulness, <verse number="20" style="v" />idolatry, sorcery, hatred, strife, jealousies, outbursts of anger, rivalries, divisions, heresies, <verse number="21" style="v" />envy, murders, drunkenness, orgies, and things like these; of which I forewarn you, even as I also forewarned you, that those who practice such things will not inherit God’s Kingdom.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="22" style="v" />But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faith,<note style="f" caller="+"></note> <verse number="23" style="v" />gentleness, and self-control. Against such things there is no law. <verse number="24" style="v" />Those who belong to Christ have crucified the flesh with its passions and lusts. <verse number="25" style="v" />If we live by the Spirit, let’s also walk by the Spirit. <verse number="26" style="v" />Let’s not become conceited, provoking one another, and envying one another.</para>
</usx>