<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="2" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />I lifted up my eyes, and saw, and behold, a man with a measuring line in his hand. <verse number="2" style="v" />Then I asked, “Where are you going?”</para>
  <para style="p">He said to me, “To measure Jerusalem, to see what is its width and what is its length.”</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="3" style="v" />Behold, the angel who talked with me went out, and another angel went out to meet him, <verse number="4" style="v" />and said to him, “Run, speak to this young man, saying, ‘Jerusalem will be inhabited as villages without walls, because of the multitude of men and livestock in it. <verse number="5" style="v" />For I,’ says Yahweh, ‘will be to her a wall of fire around it, and I will be the glory in the middle of her. <verse number="6" style="v" />Come! Come! Flee from the land of the north,’ says Yahweh; ‘for I have spread you abroad as the four winds of the sky,’ says Yahweh. <verse number="7" style="v" />‘Come, Zion! Escape, you who dwell with the daughter of Babylon.’ <verse number="8" style="v" />For Yahweh of Armies says: ‘For honor he has sent me to the nations which plundered you; for he who touches you touches the apple of his eye. <verse number="9" style="v" />For, behold, I will shake my hand over them, and they will be a plunder to those who served them; and you will know that Yahweh of Armies has sent me. <verse number="10" style="v" />Sing and rejoice, daughter of Zion; for, behold, I come, and I will dwell within you,’ says Yahweh. <verse number="11" style="v" />Many nations shall join themselves to Yahweh in that day, and shall be my people; and I will dwell among you, and you shall know that Yahweh of Armies has sent me to you. <verse number="12" style="v" />Yahweh will inherit Judah as his portion in the holy land, and will again choose Jerusalem. <verse number="13" style="v" />Be silent, all flesh, before Yahweh; for he has roused himself from his holy habitation!”</para>
</usx>