<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="1" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Paul, Silvanus, and Timothy, to the assembly of the Thessalonians in God our Father, and the Lord Jesus Christ: <verse number="2" style="v" />Grace to you and peace from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="3" style="v" />We are bound to always give thanks to God for you, brothers,<note style="f" caller="+ The word for “brothers” here and where context allows may also be correctly translated “brothers and sisters” or “siblings.”"></note> even as it is appropriate, because your faith grows exceedingly, and the love of each and every one of you towards one another abounds; <verse number="4" style="v" />so that we ourselves boast about you in the assemblies of God for your perseverance and faith in all your persecutions and in the afflictions which you endure. <verse number="5" style="v" />This is an obvious sign of the righteous judgment of God, to the end that you may be counted worthy of God’s Kingdom, for which you also suffer. <verse number="6" style="v" />Since it is a righteous thing with God to repay affliction to those who afflict you, <verse number="7" style="v" />and to give relief to you who are afflicted with us, when the Lord Jesus is revealed from heaven with his mighty angels in flaming fire, <verse number="8" style="v" />punishing those who don’t know God, and to those who don’t obey the Good News of our Lord Jesus, <verse number="9" style="v" />who will pay the penalty: eternal destruction from the face of the Lord and from the glory of his might, <verse number="10" style="v" />when he comes in that day to be glorified in his saints, and to be admired among all those who have believed, because our testimony to you was believed.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="11" style="v" />To this end we also pray always for you, that our God may count you worthy of your calling, and fulfill every desire of goodness and work of faith, with power; <verse number="12" style="v" />that the name of our Lord Jesus<note style="f" caller="+ TR adds “Christ”"></note> may be glorified in you, and you in him, according to the grace of our God and the Lord Jesus Christ.</para>
</usx>