<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="2" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />When I came to you, brothers, I didn’t come with excellence of speech or of wisdom, proclaiming to you the testimony of God. <verse number="2" style="v" />For I determined not to know anything among you, except Jesus Christ, and him crucified. <verse number="3" style="v" />I was with you in weakness, in fear, and in much trembling. <verse number="4" style="v" />My speech and my preaching were not in persuasive words of human wisdom, but in demonstration of the Spirit and of power, <verse number="5" style="v" />that your faith wouldn’t stand in the wisdom of men, but in the power of God. <verse number="6" style="v" />We speak wisdom, however, among those who are full grown; yet a wisdom not of this world, nor of the rulers of this world, who are coming to nothing. <verse number="7" style="v" />But we speak God’s wisdom in a mystery, the wisdom that has been hidden, which God foreordained before the worlds for our glory, <verse number="8" style="v" />which none of the rulers of this world has known. For had they known it, they wouldn’t have crucified the Lord of glory. <verse number="9" style="v" />But as it is written,</para>
  <para style="q">“Things which an eye didn’t see, and an ear didn’t hear,</para>
  <para style="q2">which didn’t enter into the heart of man,</para>
  <para style="q">these God has prepared for those who love him.”<note caller="+ Isaiah 64:4" style="x"></note></para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="10" style="v" />But to us, God revealed them through the Spirit. For the Spirit searches all things, yes, the deep things of God. <verse number="11" style="v" />For who among men knows the things of a man, except the spirit of the man, which is in him? Even so, no one knows the things of God, except God’s Spirit. <verse number="12" style="v" />But we received, not the spirit of the world, but the Spirit which is from God, that we might know the things that were freely given to us by God. <verse number="13" style="v" />Which things also we speak, not in words which man’s wisdom teaches, but which the Holy Spirit teaches, comparing spiritual things with spiritual things. <verse number="14" style="v" />Now the natural man doesn’t receive the things of God’s Spirit, for they are foolishness to him, and he can’t know them, because they are spiritually discerned. <verse number="15" style="v" />But he who is spiritual discerns all things, and he himself is judged by no one. <verse number="16" style="v" />“For who has known the mind of the Lord, that he should instruct him?” <note caller="+ Isaiah 40:13" style="x"></note> But we have Christ’s mind.</para>
</usx>