<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="9" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Am I not free? Am I not an apostle? Haven’t I seen Jesus Christ, our Lord? Aren’t you my work in the Lord? <verse number="2" style="v" />If to others I am not an apostle, yet at least I am to you; for you are the seal of my apostleship in the Lord. <verse number="3" style="v" />My defense to those who examine me is this. <verse number="4" style="v" />Have we no right to eat and to drink? <verse number="5" style="v" />Have we no right to take along a wife who is a believer, even as the rest of the apostles, and the brothers of the Lord, and Cephas? <verse number="6" style="v" />Or have only Barnabas and I no right to not work? <verse number="7" style="v" />What soldier ever serves at his own expense? Who plants a vineyard, and doesn’t eat of its fruit? Or who feeds a flock, and doesn’t drink from the flock’s milk? <verse number="8" style="v" />Do I speak these things according to the ways of men? Or doesn’t the law also say the same thing? <verse number="9" style="v" />For it is written in the law of Moses, “You shall not muzzle an ox while it treads out the grain.”<note caller="+ Deuteronomy 25:4" style="x"></note> Is it for the oxen that God cares, <verse number="10" style="v" />or does he say it assuredly for our sake? Yes, it was written for our sake, because he who plows ought to plow in hope, and he who threshes in hope should partake of his hope. <verse number="11" style="v" />If we sowed to you spiritual things, is it a great thing if we reap your fleshly things? <verse number="12" style="v" />If others partake of this right over you, don’t we yet more? Nevertheless we did not use this right, but we bear all things, that we may cause no hindrance to the Good News of Christ. <verse number="13" style="v" />Don’t you know that those who serve around sacred things eat from the things of the temple, and those who wait on the altar have their portion with the altar? <verse number="14" style="v" />Even so the Lord ordained that those who proclaim the Good News should live from the Good News. <verse number="15" style="v" />But I have used none of these things, and I don’t write these things that it may be done so in my case; for I would rather die, than that anyone should make my boasting void. <verse number="16" style="v" />For if I preach the Good News, I have nothing to boast about; for necessity is laid on me; but woe is to me, if I don’t preach the Good News. <verse number="17" style="v" />For if I do this of my own will, I have a reward. But if not of my own will, I have a stewardship entrusted to me. <verse number="18" style="v" />What then is my reward? That, when I preach the Good News, I may present the Good News of Christ without charge, so as not to abuse my authority in the Good News. <verse number="19" style="v" />For though I was free from all, I brought myself under bondage to all, that I might gain the more. <verse number="20" style="v" />To the Jews I became as a Jew, that I might gain Jews; to those who are under the law, as under the law, that I might gain those who are under the law; <verse number="21" style="v" />to those who are without law, as without law (not being without law toward God, but under law toward Christ), that I might win those who are without law. <verse number="22" style="v" />To the weak I became as weak, that I might gain the weak. I have become all things to all men, that I may by all means save some. <verse number="23" style="v" />Now I do this for the sake of the Good News, that I may be a joint partaker of it. <verse number="24" style="v" />Don’t you know that those who run in a race all run, but one receives the prize? Run like that, that you may win. <verse number="25" style="v" />Every man who strives in the games exercises self-control in all things. Now they do it to receive a corruptible crown, but we an incorruptible. <verse number="26" style="v" />I therefore run like that, not aimlessly. I fight like that, not beating the air, <verse number="27" style="v" />but I beat my body and bring it into submission, lest by any means, after I have preached to others, I myself should be rejected.</para>
</usx>