<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="10" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />At that time Yahweh said to me, “Cut two stone tablets like the first, and come up to me onto the mountain, and make an ark of wood. <verse number="2" style="v" />I will write on the tablets the words that were on the first tablets which you broke, and you shall put them in the ark.” <verse number="3" style="v" />So I made an ark of acacia wood, and cut two stone tablets like the first, and went up onto the mountain, having the two tablets in my hand. <verse number="4" style="v" />He wrote on the tablets, according to the first writing, the ten commandments, which Yahweh spoke to you on the mountain out of the middle of the fire in the day of the assembly: and Yahweh gave them to me. <verse number="5" style="v" />I turned and came down from the mountain, and put the tablets in the ark which I had made; and there they are as Yahweh commanded me. <verse number="6" style="v" />(The children of Israel traveled from Beeroth Bene Jaakan to Moserah. There Aaron died, and there he was buried; and Eleazar his son ministered in the priest’s office in his place. <verse number="7" style="v" />From there they traveled to Gudgodah; and from Gudgodah to Jotbathah, a land of brooks of water. <verse number="8" style="v" />At that time Yahweh set apart the tribe of Levi, to bear the ark of Yahweh’s covenant, to stand before Yahweh to minister to him, and to bless in his name, to this day. <verse number="9" style="v" />Therefore Levi has no portion nor inheritance with his brothers; Yahweh is his inheritance, according as Yahweh your God spoke to him.) <verse number="10" style="v" />I stayed on the mountain, as at the first time, forty days and forty nights: and Yahweh listened to me that time also; Yahweh would not destroy you. <verse number="11" style="v" />Yahweh said to me, “Arise, take your journey before the people; and they shall go in and possess the land, which I swore to their fathers to give to them.”</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="12" style="v" />Now, Israel, what does Yahweh your God require of you, but to fear Yahweh your God, to walk in all his ways, and to love him, and to serve Yahweh your God with all your heart and with all your soul, <verse number="13" style="v" />to keep Yahweh’s commandments and statutes, which I command you today for your good? <verse number="14" style="v" />Behold, to Yahweh your God belongs heaven and the heaven of heavens, the earth, with all that is therein. <verse number="15" style="v" />Only Yahweh had a delight in your fathers to love them, and he chose their offspring<note style="f" caller="+ or, seed"></note> after them, even you above all peoples, as it is today. <verse number="16" style="v" />Circumcise therefore the foreskin of your heart, and be no more stiff-necked. <verse number="17" style="v" />For Yahweh your God, he is God of gods, and Lord of lords, the great God, the mighty, and the awesome, who doesn’t respect persons, nor takes reward. <verse number="18" style="v" />He does execute justice for the fatherless and widow, and loves the foreigner, in giving him food and clothing. <verse number="19" style="v" />Therefore love the foreigner; for you were foreigners in the land of Egypt. <verse number="20" style="v" />You shall fear Yahweh your God; you shall serve him; and you shall cling to him, and you shall swear by his name. <verse number="21" style="v" />He is your praise, and he is your God, who has done for you these great and awesome things, which your eyes have seen. <verse number="22" style="v" />Your fathers went down into Egypt with seventy persons; and now Yahweh your God has made you as the stars of the sky for multitude.</para>
</usx>