<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="1" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />Paul, an apostle of Jesus Christ according to the commandment of God our Savior and the Lord Jesus Christ<note style="f" caller="+ NU reads"><char style="fqa" closed="false">Christ Jesus and omits </char><char style="fqa" closed="false">the Lord.</char></note> our hope; <verse number="2" style="v" />to Timothy, my true child in faith: Grace, mercy, and peace, from God our Father and Christ Jesus our Lord.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="3" style="v" />As I urged you when I was going into Macedonia, stay at Ephesus that you might command certain men not to teach a different doctrine, <verse number="4" style="v" />and not to pay attention to myths and endless genealogies, which cause disputes, rather than God’s stewardship, which is in faith— <verse number="5" style="v" />but the goal of this command is love, out of a pure heart and a good conscience and sincere faith; <verse number="6" style="v" />from which things some, having missed the mark, have turned aside to vain talking; <verse number="7" style="v" />desiring to be teachers of the law, though they understand neither what they say, nor about what they strongly affirm. <verse number="8" style="v" />But we know that the law is good, if a person uses it lawfully, <verse number="9" style="v" />as knowing this, that law is not made for a righteous person, but for the lawless and insubordinate, for the ungodly and sinners, for the unholy and profane, for murderers of fathers and murderers of mothers, for manslayers, <verse number="10" style="v" />for the sexually immoral, for homosexuals, for slave-traders, for liars, for perjurers, and for any other thing contrary to the sound doctrine; <verse number="11" style="v" />according to the Good News of the glory of the blessed God, which was committed to my trust. <verse number="12" style="v" />And I thank him who enabled me, Christ Jesus our Lord, because he counted me faithful, appointing me to service; <verse number="13" style="v" />although I was before a blasphemer, a persecutor, and insolent. However, I obtained mercy, because I did it ignorantly in unbelief. <verse number="14" style="v" />The grace of our Lord abounded exceedingly with faith and love which is in Christ Jesus. <verse number="15" style="v" />The saying is faithful and worthy of all acceptance, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners; of whom I am chief. <verse number="16" style="v" />However, for this cause I obtained mercy, that in me first, Jesus Christ might display all his patience, for an example of those who were going to believe in him for eternal life. <verse number="17" style="v" />Now to the King eternal, immortal, invisible, to God who alone is wise, be honor and glory forever and ever. Amen.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="18" style="v" />This instruction I commit to you, my child Timothy, according to the prophecies which were given to you before, that by them you may wage the good warfare; <verse number="19" style="v" />holding faith and a good conscience; which some having thrust away made a shipwreck concerning the faith; <verse number="20" style="v" />of whom are Hymenaeus and Alexander; whom I delivered to Satan, that they might be taught not to blaspheme.</para>
</usx>