<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="2" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />I exhort therefore, first of all, that petitions, prayers, intercessions, and givings of thanks, be made for all men: <verse number="2" style="v" />for kings and all who are in high places; that we may lead a tranquil and quiet life in all godliness and reverence. <verse number="3" style="v" />For this is good and acceptable in the sight of God our Savior; <verse number="4" style="v" />who desires all people to be saved and come to full knowledge of the truth. <verse number="5" style="v" />For there is one God, and one mediator between God and men, the man Christ Jesus, <verse number="6" style="v" />who gave himself as a ransom for all; the testimony in its own times; <verse number="7" style="v" />to which I was appointed a preacher and an apostle (I am telling the truth in Christ, not lying), a teacher of the Gentiles in faith and truth.</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="8" style="v" />I desire therefore that the men in every place pray, lifting up holy hands without anger and doubting. <verse number="9" style="v" />In the same way, that women also adorn themselves in decent clothing, with modesty and propriety; not just<note style="f" caller="+"></note> with braided hair, gold, pearls, or expensive clothing; <verse number="10" style="v" />but (which becomes women professing godliness) with good works. <verse number="11" style="v" />Let a woman learn in quietness with full submission. <verse number="12" style="v" />But I don’t permit a woman to teach, nor to exercise authority over a man, but to be in quietness. <verse number="13" style="v" />For Adam was first formed, then Eve. <verse number="14" style="v" />Adam wasn’t deceived, but the woman, being deceived, has fallen into disobedience; <verse number="15" style="v" />but she will be saved through her childbearing, if they continue in faith, love, and sanctification with sobriety.</para>
</usx>