<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="21" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />I saw a new heaven and a new earth: for the first heaven and the first earth have passed away, and the sea is no more. <verse number="2" style="v" />I saw the holy city, New Jerusalem, coming down out of heaven from God, prepared like a bride adorned for her husband. <verse number="3" style="v" />I heard a loud voice out of heaven saying, “Behold, God’s dwelling is with people, and he will dwell with them, and they will be his people, and God himself will be with them as their God. <verse number="4" style="v" />He will wipe away every tear from their eyes. Death will be no more; neither will there be mourning, nor crying, nor pain, any more. The first things have passed away.”</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="5" style="v" />He who sits on the throne said, <char style="wj">“Behold, I am making all things new.”</char> He said, <char style="wj">“Write, for these words of God are faithful and true.” </char> <verse number="6" style="v" />He said to me, <char style="wj">“I have become the Alpha and the Omega, the Beginning and the End.<note style="f" caller="+ TR and NU read"><char style="fqa" closed="false">“It is done! I am the Alpha and the Omega, the Beginning and the End.</char></note> I will give freely to him who is thirsty from the spring of the water of life. </char> <verse number="7" style="v" /><char style="wj">He who overcomes, I will give him these things. I will be his God, and he will be my son. </char> <verse number="8" style="v" /><char style="wj">But for the cowardly, unbelieving, sinners, abominable, murderers, sexually immoral, sorcerers,<note style="f" caller="+ The word for “sorcerers” here also includes users of potions and drugs."></note> idolaters, and all liars, their part is in the lake that burns with fire and sulfur, which is the second death.”</char></para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="9" style="v" />One of the seven angels who had the seven bowls, who were loaded with the seven last plagues came, and he spoke with me, saying, “Come here. I will show you the wife, the Lamb’s bride.” <verse number="10" style="v" />He carried me away in the Spirit to a great and high mountain, and showed me the holy city, Jerusalem, coming down out of heaven from God, <verse number="11" style="v" />having the glory of God. Her light was like a most precious stone, as if it were a jasper stone, clear as crystal; <verse number="12" style="v" />having a great and high wall; having twelve gates, and at the gates twelve angels; and names written on them, which are the names of the twelve tribes of the children of Israel. <verse number="13" style="v" />On the east were three gates; and on the north three gates; and on the south three gates; and on the west three gates. <verse number="14" style="v" />The wall of the city had twelve foundations, and on them twelve names of the twelve Apostles of the Lamb. <verse number="15" style="v" />He who spoke with me had for a measure a golden reed to measure the city, its gates, and its walls. <verse number="16" style="v" />The city is square, and its length is as great as its width. He measured the city with the reed, twelve thousand twelve stadia.<note style="f" caller="+ 12,012 stadia = or 2,221 kilometers or 1,380 miles. TR reads 12,000 stadia instead of 12,012 stadia."></note> Its length, width, and height are equal. <verse number="17" style="v" />Its wall is one hundred forty-four cubits,<note style="f" caller="+ 144 cubits is about 65.8 meters or 216 feet"></note> by the measure of a man, that is, of an angel. <verse number="18" style="v" />The construction of its wall was jasper. The city was pure gold, like pure glass. <verse number="19" style="v" />The foundations of the city’s wall were adorned with all kinds of precious stones. The first foundation was jasper; the second, sapphire;<note style="f" caller="+ or, lapis lazuli"></note> the third, chalcedony; the fourth, emerald; <verse number="20" style="v" />the fifth, sardonyx; the sixth, sardius; the seventh, chrysolite; the eighth, beryl; the ninth, topaz; the tenth, chrysoprasus; the eleventh, jacinth; and the twelfth, amethyst. <verse number="21" style="v" />The twelve gates were twelve pearls. Each one of the gates was made of one pearl. The street of the city was pure gold, like transparent glass. <verse number="22" style="v" />I saw no temple in it, for the Lord God, the Almighty, and the Lamb, are its temple. <verse number="23" style="v" />The city has no need for the sun, neither of the moon, to shine, for the very glory of God illuminated it, and its lamp is the Lamb. <verse number="24" style="v" />The nations will walk in its light. The kings of the earth bring the glory and honor of the nations into it. <verse number="25" style="v" />Its gates will in no way be shut by day (for there will be no night there), <verse number="26" style="v" />and they shall bring the glory and the honor of the nations into it so that they may enter. <verse number="27" style="v" />There will in no way enter into it anything profane, or one who causes an abomination or a lie, but only those who are written in the Lamb’s book of life.</para>
</usx>