<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><usx version="2">
  <chapter number="4" style="c" />
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="1" style="v" />After these things I looked and saw a door opened in heaven, and the first voice that I heard, like a trumpet speaking with me, was one saying, “Come up here, and I will show you the things which must happen after this.”</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="2" style="v" />Immediately I was in the Spirit. Behold, there was a throne set in heaven, and one sitting on the throne <verse number="3" style="v" />that looked like a jasper stone and a sardius. There was a rainbow around the throne, like an emerald to look at. <verse number="4" style="v" />Around the throne were twenty-four thrones. On the thrones were twenty-four elders sitting, dressed in white garments, with crowns of gold on their heads. <verse number="5" style="v" />Out of the throne proceed lightnings, sounds, and thunders. There were seven lamps of fire burning before his throne, which are the seven Spirits of God. <verse number="6" style="v" />Before the throne was something like a sea of glass, similar to crystal. In the middle of the throne, and around the throne were four living creatures full of eyes before and behind. <verse number="7" style="v" />The first creature was like a lion, and the second creature like a calf, and the third creature had a face like a man, and the fourth was like a flying eagle. <verse number="8" style="v" />The four living creatures, each one of them having six wings, are full of eyes around and within. They have no rest day and night, saying, “Holy, holy, holy<note style="f" caller="+ Hodges/Farstad MT reads “holy” 9 times instead of 3."></note> is the Lord God, the Almighty, who was and who is and who is to come!”</para>
  <para style="p">
    <verse number="9" style="v" />When the living creatures give glory, honor, and thanks to him who sits on the throne, to him who lives forever and ever, <verse number="10" style="v" />the twenty-four elders fall down before him who sits on the throne, and worship him who lives forever and ever, and throw their crowns before the throne, saying, <verse number="11" style="v" />“Worthy are you, our Lord and God, the Holy One,<note style="f" caller="+ TR omits “and God, the Holy One,”"></note> to receive the glory, the honor, and the power, for you created all things, and because of your desire they existed, and were created!”</para>
</usx>